The Blake Stern Papers
Yale University Music Library
The Blake Stern Papers
1938-1985
Misc. Ms. 307
Yale University Music Library
3.5
(5 boxes)
Programs, clippings, photographs, awards, posters, and correspondence by and about the American singer and teacher Blake Stern (1917-1987)
Stern, Blake
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open to researchers by appointment. There are no restricted materials in the collection. Please contact the Special Collections staff to schedule an appointment.
Arrangement
In 5 series as follows: I. Correspondence. II. Programs. III. Scrapbook and clippings. IV. Miscellaneous. V. Photographs.
Scope and Contents
This collection documents the career of tenor and Yale faculty member Blake Stern. The collection holds a large number of programs and clippings related to Stern's performances, as well as photographs, awards, posters, and a small number of letters.
Biographical / Historical
The tenor Blake Stern was born in Iowa in 1917. In 1940 he earned a bachelor's degree from Grinnell College. He served in the Navy during World War II, and then continued his education at the Juilliard School, where he studied with Julius Herford and Mack Harrell, receiving the M.S. in 1950. After teaching at the University of Minnesota, he joined the faculty of the Yale School of Music in 1955; he remained there for 32 years. Stern was best known as an oratorio singer. He performed with many leading orchestras and conductors in America and around the world. He died Logan, Iowa on December 22, 1987, just six months after his retirement from Yale.
Singers -- United States; Stern, Blake
- Inventory (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, Series I
  - From others to Blake Stern, I.A
    - Dr. Walter S. Collins (Dean, Michigan State University), 1 Aug. 1968 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Judith Liegner, 2 Jan. 1968 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Klaus Liepmann, 23 Oct. 1967 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Klaus Liepmann, 1 Dec. 1967 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence regarding Blake Stern, I.B
    - From Dr. Walter S. Collins to Luther Noss, 7 Aug. 1968 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Programs, Series II
  - 1938-1949 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1950-1957 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1960-1962 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 1965-1967 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - 1970-1972 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 1973-1979 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 1980-1985 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - dated, but lacks year (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Scrapbook and clippings, Series III
  General
  Clippings were copied onto acid-free paper and the originals discarded.
  - Clippings, 1940s (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Clippings, 1950s (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Clippings, 1960s (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Clippings, 1970s-1980s (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Clippings, no date (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Scrapbook from the Anchorage Festival of Music, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Miscellaneous, Series IV
  - Publicity materials (Box 2, Folder 20)
    Scope and Contents
    2 advertisements, 15 typescript pages of review excerpts.
  - Song translations, 2 songs: 4 p., 5 p. (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Diploma, Yale University, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Alumni Award, Grinnell College, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Posters of Stern performances, 12 items (Box 4)
- Photographs, Series V
  - Stern portraits with negatives, no. 1-11 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Stern portraits, no negatives, no. 12-26 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Group pictures, no. 27-32 (Box 5, Folder 26)